MOHAMED AMAAN

github.com/m-amaann

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

www.mohamed-amaan.tech

+94 771668444 | amaan.rcm@gmail.com | Colombo, Sri Lannka | <u>linkedin.com/in/mohamed-amaan</u>

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic Software Engineer with one year of experience and a solid programming foundation. Successfully complete a Full Stack Engineer internship, Proficient in Java, MERN Stack, Next.js, TypeScript, Spring Boot, .Net and AWS. Strong in data structures, algorithms, problem-solving through analytical skills, and effective communication. Committed to innovation and learning new technologies using industry trends and Agile practices.

WORK EXPERIENCE —

Harriet Pvt Ltd | Colombo 07, Sri Lanka

Feb 2024 - Sep 2024

Full Stack Engineer Intern

- Developed secure backend using .NET Core and C#, implementing RESTful APIs with HTTPS to ensure reliable and compliant data.
- Research and Integrated Payable payment gateway using ASP.NET backend, showcasing problem-solving skills and streamlining payment processes and enhancing user experience across multiple platforms.
- Implemented JWT authentication through AuthO, effectively communicating technical concepts. User sessions and securely data integrity for applications.
- Built full-stack applications with Next.js, React.js, and Spring Boot, and flutter frontend development. Agile methodologies to achieve faster deployment and improved scalability.
- Managed AWS cloud services including Amplify, EC2, RDS, and S3. and integrating Strapi Content CMS.

Aegis Lanka (Pvt) Ltd | Colombo 02, Sri Lanka

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

Data Entry Operator

- Collaborated with the team to workflows data entry processes, reducing completion on time.
- Entered and maintained large number of data into databases with work independently and a saved times.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: • HTML • CSS Java Javascript
TypeScript
C#

Technologies: React Next is
Node.is JavaEE
Spring Boot MERN Stack

> Flutter / React Native Mobile Development • Hibernate • OOP Concept

 PostgreSQL JSP / Java Servlet
Spring Security
MongoDB
MySQL

• .Net Core • Rest API • CI/CD • AWS • Angular GraphQL

 GitHub GitLab Jenkin JDBC JIRA Docker Tools: Git

EDUCATIONS

BEng (Hons) in Software Engineering

Feb 2020 - Jan 2024

London Metropolitan University (UK) GPA - 3.7/4.2

Royal College Jan - 2006 - Aug 2019

Primary to Secondary Education

PROJECTS

Customize Multvendor Harriet Shopping

Harriet Shopping Pvt Ltd

Next js, Woocommerce Rest API, AWS, Payment gateway, .Net

Feb 2024 - Present

• **Developed** a secure and scalable **Multi-Vendor Marketplace** using **Next.js**, WooCommerce **APIs**, and **Auth0**, Payable payment gatways fetched thorugh **Web API using .Net**, inventory management by 40% and enhancing user experience with a responsive, user-friendly interface.

Final Year E-Commerce React Native Mobile Application - GitHub

Mar 2023 -Nov - 2023

- Fully Built a advanced E-Commerce platform with the MERN Stack, achieving a 60% reduction in manual business processes via React Native mobile apps.
- Architected and Implemented an inventory management dashboard using React.js and integrated Stripe for streamlined payment processing, secured with JWT authentication.

Online Railway Train Booking System - GitHub

2023

• Engineered MERN stack online booking system incorporating advanced scheduling, user management, and payment processing and map tracking. Integrated 3+ third-party APIs for automated email notifications and payment gateway functionality, ensuring scalability and efficient database management.

CERTIFICATIONS

Java for Absolute Beginners Certication - UDEMY

May 2024

• Complete Spring Boot Course Certification - UDEMY

June 2024

REFERENCES

Available upon request only